{"data":[{"question":"She said, \" I was studying in the library.\" \n= She said that ___ in the library.","a":"I was studying","b":"I had been studying","c":"she was studying","d":"she had been studying","answer":"4","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to us, \" American schools begin in September.\"= He told us that American schools ___ in September.","a":"begin","b":"begun","c":"has begun","d":"had begun","answer":"1","explain":"-If reporting a general truth the present tense will be retained or even the future tense can be used","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"Jim said, \" I have been to New York.\" \n= Jim said that ___ to New York","a":"he has been","b":"he had been","c":"I had been","d":"I have been","answer":"2","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"He said, \" I am going to leave here tomorrow\" \n= He said that he ______ ______ to leave there _____ following _______.","a":"is, going, the, day","b":"is, going, a, day","c":"was, going, the, day","d":"was, going, a, day","answer":"3","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original\u00a0\n+\"\" Following day\"\" means \"\"tomorrow\"\" - day already been determined= the","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"He said, \" The earth moves round the sun.\" \n= He said that the earth ___ round the sun.","a":"move","b":"moves","c":"moved","d":"would move","answer":"2","explain":"\n- If reporting a general truth the present tense will be retained or even the future tense can be used","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"Jane said, \" I wish I were rich enough to buy this.\"= Jane said that _________ rich enough to buy that.","a":"she wish she were","b":"she wished she had been","c":"she wish she had been","d":"she wished she were","answer":"4","explain":"-  Unreal condition sentence: tense is not changed in indirect speech","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to me, \" I will come if you send for me.\" \n= He told me that ___ if ___.","a":"he will come, I send for him","b":"he would come, I sent for him","c":"he shall come, I sent for him","d":"he should come, I send for him","answer":"2","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"Last night Mary met Jane here and said, \" My brother will see you here tomorrow afternoon.\" \n= Last night Mary met Jane here and said that her brother would see her ____.","a":"there the following afternoon","b":"there this afternoon","c":"here this afternoon","d":"here the following afternoon","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Last night (said): Tomorrow afternoon \n- Today (remind what she said yesterday): This afternoon \n- Here- here: no change ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"He said to me, \" You will pass the exam next year.\" \n= He told me that I ____ the next year.","a":"should pass the exam","b":"would be pass the exam","c":"should have passed the exam","d":"shall pass the exam","answer":"1","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"I said to her, \"What are you doing now?\" \n= I asked her what ___ doing then.","a":"is she","b":"she is","c":"she was","d":"was she","answer":"3","explain":"- Indirect speech: If the reporting verb (i.e. said) is in the past, the reported clause will be in a past form. This form is usually one step back into the past from the original","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"52","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"}]}